<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Jesuits character. Written by a member of the Popish Club. ; To the Black-Smiths tune, which no body can deny.</title>
            <author>Member of the Popish Club.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B25280</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886677</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186993</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240882346</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing J712</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide Lutt.III[117]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226359</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886677</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886677e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B25280)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186993)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C6:1[119])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Jesuits character. Written by a member of the Popish Club. ; To the Black-Smiths tune, which no body can deny.</title>
                  <author>Member of the Popish Club.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year 1679.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>First line - "The Jesuits they are a sort of men (pen,".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Jesuits --  Controversial literature --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Charles II, 1660-1685 --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:186993:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>woodcut of six figures outside of heaven's gates</figDesc>
                  <p>O REX SEMPITERNE.</p>
                  <p>DELE MAL A QVE FECI</p>
                  <p>CHRE PP <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>CORESIOP<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </p>
                  <p>SA <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> OMENBANGEIORVM</p>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>The JESUITS Character.</head>
            <byline>
               <hi>Written by a Member of the</hi> POPISH CLUB.</byline>
            <opener>To the <hi>Black-Smiths</hi> Tune, <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
            </opener>
            <lg>
               <l>THE <hi>Jesuits</hi> they are a sort of Men</l>
               <l>That the Name of <hi>Jesus</hi> usurp with their Pen,</l>
               <l>In a thousand, honest are hardly ten;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Churches of God they make Dens of Thieves,</l>
               <l>They cajol the Men, and lye with their Wives,</l>
               <l>When th' are to be hang'd, none wish 'em Reprieves;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>For Christian Charity, they all despise it,</l>
               <l>But as to themselves they all will advise it;</l>
               <l>And if they once beg, he's a knave that denies i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Doctrine of <hi>Devils</hi> is all they teach,</l>
               <l>Wo be to them that come in their reach;</l>
               <l>For Murder and Treason is all that they Preach.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>In your Cities both great and fair,</l>
               <l>Where conveniences are to spare,</l>
               <l>There your <hi>Jesuits</hi> always are.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Magnificent Houses, excellent Wine,</l>
               <l>Their Bread of the whitest, and Linnen so fine,</l>
               <l>With a Cloak to the Ground they always design.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Turkies, Capons, Chickens, and Geese,</l>
               <l>Swans and Peacocks at so much apiece,</l>
               <l>For a Dinner worth <hi>Jason</hi>'s Golden Fleece.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Of Lamb and Veal, the tenderest bits,</l>
               <l>And the choicest of Mutton too by fits;</l>
               <l>These are the Books employ their wits.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thus in their Houses they keep revel Rout,</l>
               <l>Where all things go in, but nothing goes out;</l>
               <l>So merrily goes the year about.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Where ever they come they search and pry,</l>
               <l>Not a Family passage escapes their Eye,</l>
               <l>And then they report what ever they spy.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>As for high Honour and worldly Pomp,</l>
               <l>They turn up always these things Trump,</l>
               <l>And rather than lose, to the <hi>Devil</hi> will jump.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>When ever a rich Man lies a dying,</l>
               <l>The <hi>Jesuits</hi> presently they come flying,</l>
               <l>To get what they can by wheadling and lying.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>In the Courts of Princes, who but they;</l>
               <l>Among the Clergy they bear great sway,</l>
               <l>And the <hi>Devils</hi> among the Laity play.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>To bloody Revenge they still excite,</l>
               <l>For public hate, and private spite,</l>
               <l>Are chiefly the Lectures they endite.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Princes and Kings they destin to slaughter,</l>
               <l>For which they are sometimes noos'd in a Halter,</l>
               <l>Belov'd as the <hi>Devil</hi> loves Holy Water.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>For to maintain their Earthly pride,</l>
               <l>All fear of Heaven and Hell they deride,</l>
               <l>And in so doing th' are not bely'd.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>They would have murder'd our gracious King▪</l>
               <l>And was not that a most damnable thing?</l>
               <l>But some are gone to Heaven in a String.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Full many a Monarch they have kill'd,</l>
               <l>And Royal Blood have cruelly spill'd;</l>
               <l>But Providence did our Soveraign shield.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>They would have subverted our Government,</l>
               <l>And against the Nation were wickedly bent,</l>
               <l>For which reason they were to <hi>Tiburn</hi> sent.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Popery they would fain have brought in,</l>
               <l>Which says that King-killing is no Sin;</l>
               <l>But <hi>Ketch</hi> did hang them up by the Chin.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now may they all go to the <hi>Devil</hi> headlong,</l>
               <l>For then they can do us no farther wrong,</l>
               <l>Which is the conclusion of my Song.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Which no body can deny.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the Year 1679.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>